Hi everyone. In this tutorial, I'm going
to show you how to add and manage your
tasks and lists in Blitzit,
which is the core of staying organized
and productive.
Let's start with lists. Lists help you
organize your tasks by project, area of
work, or any category you like.
Think of them as folders that keep your
tasks grouped.
To create a new list, click the create
new list button in the home section.
Give your list a name,
pick an icon, adjust the color,
and hit create.
You can always edit your lists later by
clicking the three-dot menu next to the
list name.
Let's open the list.
Inside each list, tasks are organized
into columns.
They help you prioritize and schedule
your work.
You'll see columns titled today, that
shows tasks planned for the current day,
this week, that includes tasks for the
rest of the week, while the progress bar
reflects progress on both today and this
week tasks, and backlog. This one is for
the tasks scheduled beyond one week.
So, this way you know what needs your
immediate attention and what can wait.
Blitzit lets you switch between single
list view, where you focus on one
project at a time, and all lists view,
which shows all your tasks across every
list in one place.
This flexibility helps you zoom in to
stay focused on one project or get the
full picture of all of your tasks
whenever you need it.
Adding tasks is simple. Just click the
add task button, type your task, and
press enter or the confirm button.
You can add as many tasks as you want,
and move them by dragging to change the
priority.
The top tasks are your highest priority.
When you hover over a task, you can see
more options available. You can add
subtasks, add notes,
and move the task between columns with
arrow buttons.
The same thing can be done by simply
dragging and dropping the task.
The three-dot menu lets you schedule the
task, move it to another list, duplicate
it, or delete it.
Here you can also see an EST button.
By pressing it, you can add a task time
estimate. That is the time you give
yourself to complete the task.
Enter the amount of hours and minutes
and hit enter.
You can also add task time estimates
when you create a task by entering the
time in the EST field.
Note that if your task is in a live
timer, you can only add the EST while
pausing the timer.
When your task goes into a live timer,
Blitzit starts tracking time taken, the
actual time you've spent working on the
task so far.
You can also input it manually using
this field in the same format as EST.
Comparing your estimates with real time
helps you improve your planning.
When you complete a task, mark it as
done by clicking the checkbox next to
it.
You can do it from the list section. The
task will move to the done section,
giving you that satisfying sense of
progress.
Or you can do it in Blitz mode by
pressing done button in the task field.
Congrats.
Here you can see that you finished the
task 525 minutes early.
Not bad.
This way you see how many minutes early
or late you finished compared to your
EST.
Now you can move to the next task, or
maybe it's time to finally take a break.
Yeah, that's a good idea.
Check out our other tutorials on the
help center for more tips on using
different features on Blitzit to
supercharge your productivity.
And be sure to join our Discord
community. There is a lot going on that
will help you optimize your workday.
See you.